76. Prehistoric art. Prehistoric art is art from cultures that did not yet have a
written language. The first pieces of artwork are about 40,000 years old, though experts
don't agree on exactly when humans started to make art. The earliest clear works of art
come from the Upper Paleolithic era, from 10,000 to 40,000 years ago. Most art from
this era is of three types, stone figurines, cave paintings, and etchings or carvings.
Stone figurines are some of the oldest kinds of art. In fact, the oldest known piece of
art is a stone figurine called a Venus figurine. Venus figurines are small stone sculptures
of women. This particular sculpture has beautiful round curves but is not very detailed. Several
figurines like this have been found. Almost all of these sculptures have no facial features
but very detailed bodies. Prehistoric cave paintings have been found in several parts
of the world. The oldest cave paintings are in Europe, with many in Spain and France.
The paintings often show animals, especially buffalo. They also show hunting scenes. Early
painters had only five colors to use, white, black, red, brown, and yellow. But with these
colors, they created lasting works of art. Etchings and carvings are also common prehistoric
types of art. Prehistoric humans cut pictures into the walls of caves with tools. Like the
paintings, these pictures are often of animals or hunts. Some carved deer bones were found
in Korea. They may be up to 40,000 years old, which would make them some of the oldest known
art in the world. Though the tools prehistoric people had were basic, the art they made still
looks fresh and meaningful. Even 40,000 years ago, human beings wanted to have beauty in their
lives. Perhaps we aren't so different from them.